准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
挑拨离间
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
章鱼哥
Squidward
这可是你做过最好的舒芙蕾蛋糕了
this is the best soufflé you have ever created
亲亲章鱼
恭喜你  大厨
Congratulations, chef
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
派大星  你是我在这附近最好的朋友
Patrick, you're my best friend
in the whole neighborhood
派大星  你是最笨的白痴
Patrick, you are the dumbest idiot
我认识你就是我的不幸
it has ever been my misfortune to know
你真的这么觉得吗  海绵宝宝
Do you really think that, SpongeBob?
那当然了  派大星
Of course, Patrick
有眼睛的都能看出来
Anyone with eyes could see that
那好  我觉得你很丑
Yeah, well, I think you're ugly
黄色丑得很
Yellow is ugly
派大星  你到底在说什么
Patrick, what are you talking about?
海绵宝宝  我再也不想认识你了
SpongeBob, I no longer wish to know you
你玷污了海底居民这个名号
You give bottom dwellers a bad name
但凡你每无脑一次我都能赚一块钱
If I had a dollar for every brain you don't have
那我还真赚到这块钱了
I'd have one dollar
派大星  我听说宠物店那边有份工作
Hey, Patrick, I heard there was a job
opening down at the pet shop
可以当垫屁股用的报纸
as some newspaper
你这话显得你像个大笨蛋  你这笨蛋
That makes you a big dummy, you dummy
是是是  这就表示
Yeah, well, that means that
你也一样笨
so are you
对  你就是个白痴
Right, you're a turkey
那是什么
What's that?
那就是你
It's what you are
那你就是更大的白痴
Well, you're a bigger one
你还是黄色的
Well, you're still yellow
知道还有什么东西是黄色的吗
You know what else is yellow?
什么
What?
就是你
You are
是吗
Yeah?
那我也不稀罕你怎么叫我了
Well, it doesn't matter what you call me
反正我再也不想看到你了
'cause I never want to see you again anyway
真该死
Tartar sauce
章鱼哥  你噎着了
Squidward, you're choking
我知道要怎么办
I know what to do
不过我得先去洗个手
but I should wash my hands first
好吧
Oh, well
我赢了
I win
派大星
Patrick
你救了我
You saved me
有吗
I did?
没错
Yep
你真是个救命恩人  朋友
You're a real lifesaver, friend
朋友
Friend?
Friend
对  派大星
Yeah, Patrick
我们是朋友
We're friends
普通朋友
Just friends
那我们今晚要做什么呢  最好的朋友
So, what are we going to do tonight, best friend?
我要练我的竖笛独奏
Well, I was going to practice my clarinet solo
竖笛
Clarinet?
我好爱音乐
I love music
谁需要他们啊
Who needs them?
反正他们也没意思  对吧小蜗
They're no fun anyway, right, Gary?
小蜗
Gary?
章鱼哥将要演奏
Squidward will be performing
自己改编的e小调独奏曲
his version of "Solitude in E Minor"
好耶
Yeah
e小调  太好了
"E minor", all right, yeah
我在担心什么啊
What am I worried about?
我朋友多得很
I got plenty of friends
我可以一口气说出三个名字
I can name three right off the bat
全都到齐了
The gang's all here
我的腰
My back
我闪到腰了
I threw out my back
好啊
Oh, boy
我的机会来了
Now's my chance
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
不要  别过来
No, no, stay back
你放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我来了
I'm coming
不
No
离我远点
Get away from me
撑住  我来救你了
Hang on, I'll save you
别
No
别过来
Get away from me
别
No
撑住
Hold on
不
No
走开
Get away
我完蛋了
I'm ruined
我
I--
我感觉好舒服
I feel great
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
你是个真正的朋友
You're a real friend
朋友
Friend
不不不
No, no, no
没那意思
I didn't mean that
不
No
你放心  章鱼哥兄弟
Don't worry, Squiddy old pal
朋友之间就该这样
That's what friends are for
笨蛋派大星在你家睡着了是吧
So dumb Patrick fell asleep on you, huh?
某些朋友啊
Some friend
真正的朋友会为你演奏
A real friend would perform for you
你来吹
You play?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我多年以来都在拉童车呢
I've been playing bassinet for years
[ 低音提琴为double bass
此处"bassinet"为误称 ]
给我一个A音  兄弟
Give me an A buddy
章鱼哥是我全世界最好的朋友
Squidward is my best friend in the world
章鱼哥是我全海洋最好的朋友
Squidward is my best friend in the sea
章鱼哥
Squidwar--
比起海绵宝宝更喜欢派大星
Likes Patrick More than SpongeBob
派大星是个脏又臭的烂朋友  章鱼哥
Patrick is a dirty, stinky, rotten friend, Squidward
我可以修好的
I can fix this
那
So, uh
明天再见了  章鱼哥
I'll see you tomorrow, Squidward
打我电话
Call me
真是太恶心了
That was disgusting
我好想把自己擦干净
Feel like I need to scrub myself
兄弟  我帮你预热了一下
Hey, buddy, I warmed it up for you
派大星  滚出去
Patrick, get out
顺便把衣服穿上
And put some clothes on
怎么了  章鱼哥大兄弟
What's the matter, Squidward, old buddy?
居然发现了这种肮脏勾当
So this is what I find, huh?
我最好的朋友和前任最好的朋友还有
My best friend and my ex-best friend and
一堆橡皮浴缸玩具
rubber bath toys
是吗
Oh, yeah?
他可是我朋友
Well, he was my friend
我怎么会碰上这种事
This can't be happening to me
章鱼哥
Squidward
兄弟
Buddy
章鱼哥  你在哪
Squidward, where are you?
烦死了
This is nuts
我要有个计划来让那两个和好
I need a plan to get those two back together
然后不再烦我
and out of my hair
章鱼哥
Squidward
晚宴
A dinner party?
我想去
I'd love to
你想念我了吗
Did you miss me?
进来吧
Come on in
你样子不错
You look stunning
我宁愿跟你一块吃饭
I'd much rather dine with you
也不跟那个垃
than that lousy
怎么回事
Say, what gives?
我不跟那个疯子坐
I'm not sitting near that maniac
我也一样
Me, neither
这都是圈套
This was a setup
你们两个不是我最好的朋友吗
I thought you two were my best friends
我才是你最好的朋友
I am your best friend
那要不要来点苏打水  两位
Well, how about some soda, guys?
来点吧
Yes, please
谢了  朋友
Thanks, friend
要不要给你最好的朋友来一点
How about some for your best friend?
谢了  最好的朋友
Thanks, best friend
我现在能来点了吗  兄弟
Can I have some now, buddy?
等等
Wait
我还要苏打水
I need some more
我还没喝到
I still didn't get any
给你
There you go
再来点
More, please
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
派大星  你杯子满出来了
Patrick, your glass is full
啊对
Oh, yeah
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
来点  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
两位抱歉
Sorry, boys
苏打水都喝光了
I'm all out of pop
我去再装一点过来
I'm going to go get some more
要不你们就先在这聊会天吧
Why don't you just stay here and chat?
我应该马上走开
I should just walk away right now
真是惊喜啊
What a surprise
我请他们过来  让他俩单独待我家
I invited them in and I left them alone
章鱼哥  今天学到了什么教训
Well, Squidward, what have we learned today?
你猜怎么着  章鱼哥
Guess what, Squidward?
我跟海绵宝宝又是朋友了
Me and SpongeBob are friends again
太棒了
Great
滚别处交友去
Go be friends somewhere else
你不想要我们帮你清理一下吗
Don't you want us to help you clean this up a little?
不想
No
滚
Out
他应该是嫉妒了
I think he's jealous
太可悲了
How pathetic
我的背
My back
滑浪学校
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
到了  小蜗
This is it, Gary
三月
今日驾考
驾考就是今天了
The big boating exam is today
我从来没觉得这么有能力过
I've never felt so capable
我准备好了
I'm ready
章鱼哥
Squidward
什么
What?
我准备好了  章鱼哥
I'm ready, Squidward
准备好搬走了吗
Ready to move?
不对  是准备好去过驾考了
No, I'm ready to pass my boating test
我准备好了
I'm ready
滑浪学校
我准备好了好了
I'm ready-eady
准备好了
ready
兄弟  我再也用不着你了
Well, pal, I won't be needing you anymore
我准备好了
I'm ready
好耶
Oh, yeah
我准备好了
I'm ready
好
Yes
我刚考到驾照了
I just got my license
我等下也要考到了
I'm getting mine next
这可不见得
I doubt it
好
Okay
马路上见
See you on the road
我准备好了
I'm ready
我来了  泡芙老师
Here I come, Mrs. Puff
我准备好了
I'm ready
我没准备好
I'm not ready
泡芙老师好
Hi, Mrs. Puff
今天是我要过驾考的日子
Today is the day I'm going to pass my boating exam
那就考考看  海绵宝宝
We'll see about that, SpongeBob
首先必须
First we must--
首先必须通过科目一
First I must pass the oral exam
我对我能力有信心  绝对能成功通过
I am confident in my ability to successfully succeed
我知道
I know
好  第一题
Okay, number one
船的前部是什么
What is the front of the boat?
船头
The bow
后部是什么
What is the back?
船尾
Stern
第三题  右侧是
Number three, right is--
右舷
Starboard
左舷
port
船长
skipper
甲板
deck
船舱
cabin
厨房
galley
龙骨
keel
你通过科目一了
You've passed the oral test
太惊喜了
What a surprise
现在你又要参加科目二了
Now it's time to once again
take the driving portion of the exam
好的  海绵宝宝
Okay, SpongeBob
上船
Get in the boat
这艘船  就这边
In this boat, right here?
时间到了吗
Is it time already?
快上船  海绵宝宝
Get in the boat, SpongeBob
对  要上船
Oh, yeah, absolutely
你现在要做的就是上路
All you have to do is get on the track
好的  海绵宝宝
Okay, SpongeBob
首先你应该要做什么
What's the first thing you do?
1924?
不对
No, no
首先应该要把船发动
First thing is to start the boat
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  别紧张
SpongeBob, relax
只是艘船而已
It's only the boat
船
The boat?
好的  那接下来要做什么
Okay, now, what do you do next?
油门踩到底
Floor it?
对
Yes--
不
No
不对  不要踩油门
No, don't floor it
油门踩到底
Floor it?
不不不  不要
No, no, no, don't
踩油门
floor it
好  油门踩到底
Okay, floor it
不
No
踩到底
Floor it
半壳
海绵宝宝  为什么
Oh, SpongeBob, why?
我的腿
My leg
我不知道这是为什么  小蜗
I don't know why, Gary
我不知道
I don't know
我挂驾考已经挂烦了
I'm tired of failing that boating test
我已经都考了37次了
I've already taken it 37 times
小蜗
好吧  38次
Okay, 38
不行  小蜗
No, Gary
我绝不步行
I'm not walking
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我是海星突击队员  完毕
This is star ranger, over
什么事  派大星
What is it, Patrick?
我有份惊喜要给你
I got a surprise for you
派大星  我没这个心情
Oh, Patrick, I'm not in the mood
快起床
Get out of bed
好
Okay
现在呢  派大星
Now what, Patrick?
到你壁橱那儿准备惊喜吧
Go to your closet for a surprise
好  我到壁橱了
Okay, I'm at the closet
仔细听好了
Listen carefully
什么东西又粉又方
What's pink and square at the same time?
不知道  派大星
I don't know, Patrick
派大星宝宝
Patrick SquarePants
派大星  别这样
Pat, don't do that
我现在烦心得很
I've got too much to worry about
有什么问题
What's the problem?
我过不了驾考
I can't pass my boating exam
我已经考了37
I've taken it 37--
38次了
38 times
我本来还知道所有答案
I know all the answers
结果一上船就全忘光了
until I get behind the wheel
我要有样东西让我思路清楚
I just need something to help me think straight
我思路就清楚得很
Thinking straight is what I do
你来开船  我来帮你想答案
You drive, and I'll do all the thinking for you
那要怎样才能办到
How are we going to do that?
请回答  海绵宝宝
Come in, SpongeBob
喂
Hello
我能从脑袋里听见你声音
I can hear you in my head
真是太棒了
This is great
我驾考的时候
While I'm taking the test
你可以告诉我所有答案
you can give me all the answers
等一下  派大星
Wait a minute, Patrick
脑门上伸出个天线会不会显得我很傻
Won't I look silly with this antenna
coming out of my head?
海星呼叫海绵
Pat to Sponge
测试
Testing
测  测
Test, test
收到了没
Do you read?
海绵呼叫海星
Sponge to Pat
已清晰响亮收到  完毕
I read you loud and clear, over
准备好苹果了没
Got your apple ready?
幸运内裤
Lucky undergarments?
等下  等下
Hold on, hold on
行了
Bingo
幸运
内裤  苹果
Underwear, apple
还有我
and me
你已经做好考到驾照的准备了
You're ready to get that license
泡芙老师来了
Here comes Mrs. Puff
表现自然点
Act natural
不对
No, no
上船
Get in the boat
把苹果给她
Give her the apple
给你  老师
Here you go, ma'am
赶快这事过了吧
Let's get this over with
首先你应该做什么
What's the first thing you do?
把船发动
Start the boat
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff
什么
What?
没事  只是艘船而已
It's okay, it's only the boat
船
The boat
你把船发动了
You started the boat?
我
I--
应该是吧
I think so
那
Well--
你接下来会做什么
What's the second thing you do?
1924?
不对
No, no
挂前进挡
Put it in drive
Put it in drive?
对对对
Yes, yes, yes
挂前进挡
Put it in drive
然后呢
Then what?
踩油门
Floor it?
不对
No, no
不要动  先生
Freeze, mister
大脚趾
Big toe
好家伙
Gracious
居然还没撞车
We haven't crashed yet
好的  即将到达第一条弯道
Okay, you're coming to your first turn
墙
不好  第一条弯道
Oh, no, the first turn
墙
求你告诉我你知道
Please, tell me you know
在第一条弯道要怎么做
what to do at the first turn
左
Left
右
Right
天啊
My
绝妙无比  海绵宝宝
This is splendid, SpongeBob
你表现很好
You're doing fine
停
我的日记
姓名    海绵宝宝
绝妙
Splendid
好极了
Wonderful
终点线
终点线到了
There's the finish line
实在难以置信
It's unbelievable
我见过的所有学生里
You've shown the most spectacular improvement
就你进步最大
of any student I've ever seen
你有什么秘诀
What's your secret?
脑袋里装了个无线电吗
A little radio in your head?
帽子底下的是不是天线什么的
And under that hat is some kind of antenna?
几里开外还有个人
And some guy miles away from here
把答案都告诉了你
is giving you all the answers
没错
Oh, yes
但那都是作弊行为
But that would be cheating
作弊
Cheating
我这是作弊吗
I'm cheating?
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff?
怎么了  我的优秀学生
Yes, my star pupil?
我好像作弊了
I think I'm cheating
怎么了  亲爱的
What's that, dear?
我好像作弊了
I think I am cheating
你
You--
你没握方向盘
You've let go of the wheel
我帽子底下还真有条天线
I do have an antenna under my hat
还有人把答案全告诉我了
There is a guy giving me all the answers
全都是真的
It's all true
我作弊了
I'm cheating
什么
What?
对不起  泡芙老师
I'm sorry, Mrs. Puff
对不起
I'm sorry
方向盘  海绵宝宝
The wheel, SpongeBob
方向盘
The wheel
终点线
作弊了
Cheating
我是个骗子  骗子
I'm a cheater, cheater
不
No
终点线
没事的  你可以作弊
It's all right, you can cheat
不行  我作弊了
No, I'm cheating
往那开  海绵宝宝
That way, SpongeBob
我作弊了
I'm cheating
要作弊往那开
Cheat that way
骗子骗子  吃南瓜蛋子
Cheater, cheater, pumpkin eater
没事的  只要
It's okay, just--
不行
No
往那开
That way
要作弊往那开
Cheat that way
骗子
Cheater
海绵宝宝  为什么
Oh, SpongeBob, why?
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff?
我好像作弊了
I think I cheated
我的腿
My leg
抱歉又让你失望了  泡芙老师
I'm sorry for letting you down again, Mrs. Puff
没事  海绵宝宝
It's okay, SpongeBob
你不是有意的
You didn't mean it
行了  带我走吧
Okay, boys, take me away
你放心  泡芙老师
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff
我下学期会更努力的
I'll try harder next semester
会好起来的
It'll be great
这下我连自行车都没了
Only now I don't even have my bike
小蜗
Gary
我的自行车
My bike
你找到了
You've found it
这个海绵还有车开
This sponge is still mobile
去给住院的泡芙老师来个惊喜吧
All right, let's go surprise someone at the hospital